petro-canada.ca 2006-06-17

# Petro-Canada Privacy Policy

  |  |    
  |  | Home » Privacy Policy  
---  
|     
---  

| Petro-Canada Privacy Policy  
  
---  
|   
---  
  
Respecting and protecting your privacy is important to us and a priority in our continuing relationship.

Petro-Canada collects your personal information through various means, such as through your purchases of Petro-Canada products, your enrollment in our Petro-Points loyalty program, Web site cookies, and your response to our surveys.

Petro-Canada collects this information so that we can carry out one or more of the following:

  * Administer the Petro-Points program; 
  * Provide you with ongoing services relating to your purchases of Petro-Canada products, including, but not limited to, fuel, lubricants, car care, warranties and other offerings; 
  * Include you in preferred customer activities, such as special promotions and bonus offers; 
  * Manage, develop and improve our business and operations; 
  * Complete the necessary credit investigation(s) when you are applying for credit (i.e., Petro-Canada SuperPass credit card,  other commercial credit cards, or wholesale account); 
  * Assist in the development and marketing of our products and services; and 
  * To comply with any legal or regulatory requirements, or to cooperate with police and/or financial institutions during any investigation of credit/debit card and/or suspected criminal/fraudulent activities involving Petro-Canada or any of Petro-Canada's service providers or agents.

Petro-Canada takes great care to ensure your personal information is securely stored. Access to this information is restricted to authorized personnel of Petro-Canada. Your personal information is held in confidence by Petro-Canada, its subsidiaries and affiliates, and by any company that acquires Petro-Canada or some or all of its retail stations, and will only be disclosed to Petro-Canada's program partners (including its partners in the Petro-Points program as set out in the Rewards Guide), or to third-party agents responsible for administering our programs or special offers, provided that such companies use the information only for the purposes for which it was disclosed, and agree to comply with Petro-Canada's privacy policy.

Please note that your personal information that you disclose on a Petro-Canada SuperPass or other commercial credit card application will only be used to complete the necessary credit investigation and will not be used for marketing or other purposes, unless we ask for and receive your consent for such use(s).

If you wish to have your name removed from our telephone, mail or e-mail marketing lists, please call us at 1-800-668-0220 or send an e-mail to [custsvs@petro-canada.ca](mailto:custsvs@petro-canada.ca).  Please keep in mind that removing your name from our marketing lists makes you ineligible for added bonus points and special offers. You may also contact us in the same manner for more information regarding our privacy policy and procedures or to request access to or correct any of your personal information held by Petro-Canada.

**Other Stakeholders**

Respecting and protecting the privacy of Petro-Canada’s other stakeholder group is important to us and is a priority in our continuing relationship. Examples of other stakeholders include, but are not limited to, individual contractors, job applicants, landowners, lease-grantors, shareholders, investment analysts, government contacts and scholarship recipients.

Petro-Canada collects your personal information through various means, such as through personal contact, job and scholarship applications, over the phone and through Web site cookies. We collect this information so we can manage our ongoing relationship with you, but we will tell you the specific purposes for which your information will be used when we collect it. 

Petro-Canada takes great care to ensure your personal information is securely stored. Access to this information is restricted to authorized employees of Petro-Canada and will only be disclosed to third-party agents responsible for administering our programs or providing Petro-Canada with services, provided that such companies use the information only for the purposes for which it was disclosed, and agree to maintain privacy policies consistent with Petro-Canada’s. 

For more information regarding our privacy policy and procedures please contact us by telephone at 1-866-431-9868 or by e-mail at [privacy@petro-canada.ca](mailto:privacy@petro-canada.ca). You may also contact us in the same manner to request access to or correct any of your personal information held by Petro-Canada.  
  
|  Cookies  
---  
A cookie is a piece of data – typically encoded information about how and when you use a site – that a Web server creates when you visit a Web site. This data is placed on your computer hard drive in the form of a small text file. 

There are two types of cookies: session cookies and persistent cookies. Session cookies are used only for the length of time you stay on the Web site. When you leave the site, they expire and are no longer active. Persistent cookies are more permanent and can be re-read when you return to the site that placed them on your computer. We use persistent cookies in one instance only – to identify previous visits to a new section of the Web site so that you are not required to view redirect information on subsequent visits.

The Petro-Points section of the Petro-Canada Web site uses session cookies to enable us to better serve Petro-Points members. You must enable cookies for this section of the Web site to function correctly. Petro-Canada does not use cookies to track any personal information about you, nor to collect any marketing data.

We do not and will not use cookies to retrieve data from your hard drive or to obtain your e-mail address or other personal information. 

You may choose not to accept cookies by setting your browser options to inform you when cookies are being sent. Alternately, you can set these options to deny cookies altogether. Please note, however, that by not accepting cookies you may limit the functionality that we can provide to you when you visit our site. 

To change your browser settings:   

  * Microsoft Internet Explorer 4: Select Options from the Internet Options. Select the Advanced menu and scroll to the Cookies section. You will have several options - accept cookies, ask permission before accepting cookies or disallow cookies.    

  * Microsoft Internet Explorer 5: Select Tools from your browser menu. Select Internet Options, Security, then Internet from the Web Content Zone, then select Custom Level. From the drop-down list, scroll down to Cookies and select the options you want.    

  * Microsoft Internet Explorer 6: On the Tools menu, click Internet Options, and then click the Privacy tab. Under Settings, move the slider to the privacy level you want.   

  * Netscape Communicator or Navigator: Select Preferences from the Edit menu. From the Preferences menu, select Advanced, and several cookie options will be listed in the lower right of the menu. There will be options that allow you to accept cookies, request permission before accepting or disallow cookies completely. 

|  Automatic Logging of Session Data  
---  
To help us serve you better, we continuously and automatically collect generic, non-personal information about visits to our Web site. The following points describe the nature of the information collected in our Web server logs: 

  * We do not collect personal information such as names, ages, phone numbers, addresses or e-mail addresses from visitors to our Web site. We do not collect individual profile information for visitors across multiple sites and do not aggregate information from any other sources about browsing patterns of individual visitors across multiple sites.  

  * We collect anonymous visitor information like IP addresses, browser types (such as Internet Explorer or Netscape), return visits from past guests, referring pages, pages visited along with the order in which they were visited, time spent on the Web site, and the referrer and transaction information for e-commerce pages. We collect such non-personally identifiable information for the following purposes: (1) to obtain anonymous statistical analysis of Web page traffic patterns for our Web site (2) to administer our Web site and servers, (3) to allow for auditing of our services by third parties, and (4) to improve our services.  

  * As mentioned above, we use cookies only for more accurate anonymous traffic analysis As we do not build a database of individual visitors, the data that we do collect is never stored in any individual user profile; the data collected serves only to update aggregate counts allowing us to monitor traffic on our Web site.  

  * We make use of customized JavaScript tracking code to track anonymous information about visitors' activity. This code contacts our suppliers’ servers, receives a cookie in response, and loads an image to the page. This 1 x 1 image is called a clear gif or Web bug. This JavaScript tracking code does not collect personal information such as name, age, phone number, mailing address or credit card numbers from visitors to our Web site. Visitors may elect to opt out of receiving tracking cookies used to collect information for our Web server logs. Note: the opt out option requires one cookie to function.  

  * We do not create individual profiles of visitors. We do not have a database of individual profiles of each visitor. We collect data in aggregate form and data is not recorded or stored about individual visitors.  

  * We may use the aggregate data to inform third parties as to the number of people who have seen and clicked on links to their Web sites. 

Petro-Canada reserves the right to change this policy at any time. Please check this page periodically for changes.

Updated Tuesday, Jan. 17, 2006 at 1:41 p.m. EST.  

  |  |
